[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS]
♪♪
[POLICE RADIO CHATTER]
SHERIFF: Hey, Hatcher.
Coroner's finished with
the scatter at the tree line.
Probably got another seven
or eight down there.
So they're released?
Yep. All yours.
♪♪
The feds say we're clear.
Start bringing the victims up.
Take a team to the tree line
and start moving 'em to the morgue.
♪♪
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS]
♪♪
TECH: Here's the next one, Hatcher.
HATCHER: Hello, Mr. Geller.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS IN DISTANCE]
♪♪
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
- Hey.
- Hello.
You must be Crystal.
One and only.
You look different
than your profile picture.
You look the same.
Better.
[CHUCKLES LIGHTLY]
Please. Why don't you come in.
I don't understand.
Over the phone, you said...
- I know what I said.
- If you're a cop...
Please, I didn't ask you here
[INHALES DEEPLY] for sex.
Not like you think.
It's something different.
I'm leaving.
Angela, sit down.
How do you know my real name?
Who are you?
I'm someone who knows more about you
than you might want to believe.
I know about your father.
I know about the medical debt,
the collectors.
I said who are you?
Angela, there is something
that I would like to tell you.
Something very special
that might just change your life.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS]
Would you like to hear about it?
♪♪
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
♪♪ _
ESI JACKSON: Already looked there.
There, too.
♪♪
You do know I'm a private investigator.
You were made.
Ilya obviously knew
you were watching him.
Maybe that wouldn't have happened
if you'd been honest
about why you hired me.
I was honest.
I hired you to find Koslov
so I could question him.
Does this look like a man
who's running from questions?
He's running for his life.
Now, why would he do that?
♪♪
SADIQ ASMAL: They came here
to the mosque,
said that some of our members
are communicating
with Syrian jihadists.
The FBI came?
Counterterrorism division.
They wouldn't tell me what they know.
Maybe they'll tell you.
He knows about the Task Force.
Does he?
I wouldn't be much of a shepherd
if I didn't know the hearts
and minds of my flock.
- [CELLPHONE RINGS]
- [SIGHS] Excuse me.
I'll see what I can do.
[RINGING CONTINUES]
[BEEP]
Is it done?
My job is to find people,
not to keep them from being found.
- Is it done?
- It is.
Wherever Koslov went,
she's never gonna find him.
Good.
[BEEP]
Imam Asmal is grateful for the help.
We both are.
Elizabeth knows I'm not Ilya.
I wonder what else she knows.
Perhaps you should ask her.
She's waiting in the park.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
You have a case.
From my days in the Mobile Psych Unit.
I'd like to dig into it.
If it's important to you,
then it's important to me.
You're sure you don't mind?
Of course not.
That's what's so nice
about us finally being
on the same side of things, same agenda.
No subterfuge.
What you want, I want.
And you're okay with my
involving the team.
I am. In fact, I insist.
Idle hands and all that.
But I would like you to look
into something for me.
Of course.
It's about Dembe's... imam.
- Is there something wrong?
- I don't know yet.
That's what I need to find out.
But first, tell me about this
cold case of yours.
They called him the Boneyard Killer.
His first victim was found
just outside Rehoboth Beach
when local police exhumed a body
for autopsy.
What they found was a second
body buried in that same grave.
A young woman
four feet below the surface,
resting just above
a freshly buried coffin...
murdered and hidden
in the last place
anyone would ever look for her.
Since then, three women
have been discovered this way
in graveyards in Virginia
and West Virginia.
He was using the cemeteries as dumpsites.
Anything significant about
the graves that were chosen?
- They were fresh. Easy to dig.
- And the victims?
All young women
with a history of sex work.
ARAM: Okay, this is, uh, terrible,
but sex workers are
like 20 times more likely
to be targeted by serial killers.
True, but none of his victims
were sexually assaulted,
no sign of defensive wounds,
no pre- or postmortem mutilation.
But the way he killed them...
we found dirt in their airways.
They were alive when he buried them.
Alive, yes.
- [CELLPHONE RINGING]
- And unconscious.
Pumped so full of sodium thiopental,
- they'd never wake up.
- PARK: I don't understand.
He drugged them so they'd die
in their sleep?
- Why would he do that?
- He didn't want them to suffer.
LIZ: The case went cold until a week ago,
when flash floods hit Montgomery
and upended a few graves
at Greenfare Cemetery,
including one unidentified body
that wasn't supposed to be there.
Initial forensics suggest she was sedated
and buried alive just like the others.
Has the Bureau reached out to you?
No, and they're not going to.
They asked me to leave the case.
They said my profile wasn't... additive.
- So this is your cold case.
- Yes.
What do you mean they thought
your profile wasn't "additive"?
I don't think he wants to kill.
I think he's mimicking these profiles
in order to hide some other agenda.
What, I don't know,
but I think he finds satisfaction
in something other than the act
of the crime itself.
Whatever his motive,
these bodies were found by chance,
and we can't wait for another.
Talk to the M.E. See what he knows.
Let's hope this newest tragedy
will help you find this guy.
Uh, sir, can I ask for another favor?
Reddington says that counterterrorism
is sniffing around Dembe's imam.
He wants to know what they found.
What were they looking for?
Syrian jihadists.
Some of the congregants may be
involved with Tahrir al-Sham.
But Dembe thinks that's impossible.
I'll make a few calls.
Ilya Koslov is out there somewhere,
and I have no idea where.
Do you know what your mother
wanted from him?
I don't. But she said
her life depended on it.
[DOOR OPENS]
You were right.
I looked at the original case files,
and this does appear to be
the work of the same killer.
I have ID'd her as one Mara Lynne James.
Now, the forensic evidence
on your previous victims
was limited, but this woman...
the cold slowed the growth of bacteria,
so I have a better picture
of what happened.
Suffocation?
With sodium thiopental
to sedate her beforehand.
Soil in the lungs.
Same lack of any defensive wounds.
Was there any evidence of sexual assault?
No, but she was sexually active.
She had a baby.
The degree of scarring
around the incision
suggests she gave birth
no more than a month
before she was killed.
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
♪♪
Okay, now one more big push.
- C'mon. You can do it.
- Come on. Push.
[GASPS]
[WATER SLOSHING]
You did it.
Is everything okay?
Isn't he supposed to cry or some...
- [BABY CRIES]
- Yes, she is.
It's a girl.
Rest. Please.
We have work to do.
[BABY CRIES SOFTLY]
♪♪
I tried to get off the streets.
We both did.
We had every resource to help her.
We apologize for coming
at such a difficult time.
We're sorry for your loss.
RESSLER: We want you to know
that we've deployed
our Child Abduction Response team
and alerted every law enforcement agency
in the country.
What for?
To find Mara's child.
Mara didn't have a child.
According to the M.E., she gave
birth a month before she passed.
A baby?
Did she have a man in her life?
A man? [SCOFFS]
You do know what she did for a living?
Did she talk about anyone in particular?
Yeah, she talked.
She talked all the time.
None of it was ever true.
Nancy James, if you know something
that could help that child...
[SIGHS]
A year ago...
10 months maybe,
she said she met a guy,
[SCOFFS] a big fish.
- Did she tell you his name?
- No.
Just that he had a plan.
A way for her to get out.
COOPER: CTD and MPD will be here in 20.
I can't hold them off any longer.
Did the Bureau do this?
Has my imam been arrested?
CTD says no, but based on their findings,
maybe they should've.
The case file Agent Keen asked for.
Apparently, two members
have been smuggling
shipping containers in and out of Syria.
- For Tahrir al-Sham?
- Unclear.
We don't know what's being
shipped or by whom.
These members in the file.
I've seen them at the services.
- I don't see them as a threat.
- Then where are they?
As soon as you called about the
abduction, we put out a BOLO.
But it appears as if they're long gone.
Along with Imam Asmal.
The Bureau didn't do him any favors
by questioning him here in the mosque.
Made it appear as if he knew
something and might talk.
Can you be sure he didn't know?
If he said he didn't know,
he didn't know.
What was the port of origin?
Latakia, Syria. Why?
Ironically, smuggling on a large scale
is a profitable
yet surprisingly small club.
And ever since civil war
broke out in Syria,
the margins on everything
from weapons to medical supplies
to narcotics to food
going in and out of the country
have been particularly bodacious.
As such, there's plenty of room
for all the players.
Turf has been designated.
Territory agreed upon.
Who got Latakia?
A Greek fellow from Queens.
A-And Greece.
[BABY COOING]
How's Mom? You doing okay?
Great.
Can't stop staring at her.
She is adorable. You're blessed.
I'm gonna run to the store,
but there was a call
while you two were asleep.
I didn't want to wake you.
An attorney. Geoffrey Entz.
He said you would know
what it was regarding.
Such a cute baby.
I'll see you soon.
[BABY FUSSING]
♪♪
[CELLPHONE RINGS]
[BEEP]
ANGELA: I talked to him.
The lawyer? What did he say?
That he got the letter,
but he didn't want to discuss it
over the phone.
Did he ask to meet?
Yes, but I-I didn't think it
would be this soon.
- I'm not prepared.
- I told you, Angela.
I have it all worked out.
Like a script.
I'll coach you through everything.
Listen, I'm not in a good place
to talk right now,
so let me call you back.
[BEEP]
♪♪
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS]
ARAM: I think I may have something.
As you may know, genetic material passes
from mother to child during pregnancy,
but what you may not know
is it also happens in reverse.
Fetal cells cross the placenta
and enter the mother's body,
making up as much as 10%
of the free-floating DNA
- in her bloodstream.
- How does that help us?
Well, with the M.E.'s help,
I was able to run the fetal DNA
from Mara James
against databases
from genetic testing services.
And with almost absolute certainty,
the father of her child is...
Jonathan McClaire.
- The self-help guru?
- The same.
Author of six books.
He runs workshops all around the world.
A married man living a public life
has a child with a prostitute?
Bring him in.
Find out what he has to say.
Right, uh, about that. Here's the thing.
He didn't kill her.
Well, how do you know that?
Because he died 11 months before
Mara James was murdered.
♪♪
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Kendra, what I am offering you
- is a chance to change your life.
- [SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE]
A way out.
And forget about debt
or your car payments.
This is far more than that.
If you can imagine,
I am the last man that you ever
have to meet in a hotel room.
Ever.
How much are we talking about?
♪♪
Tell me again how this works.
That's it!
Mr. Korba, what a pleasure!
Your reputation precedes you.
Mine may not, so allow me
to introduce myself.
I know who you are. You don't scare me.
[LAUGHS]
My heavens.
Is that A5 olive wagyu?
I didn't know you did business in Japan.
Or did these just fall off
a truck somewhere
on their circuitous journey
to Nobu Damascus?
I'm a legitimate businessman.
Yes, I'm sure you are.
But as it happens,
I'm not necessarily
interested in your beef.
I'm really here to discuss
Jalal Abbas and his friends,
and whatever they're bringing
into the country from Syria.
I may have the face of an angel,
but I'm not telling you anything.
On the contrary,
I think you're going to tell me
where they are
and what they're smuggling.
You think you're the first guy
to threaten me?
I'm not threatening you, Costas.
I'm threatening your livelihood.
Did you know these cows
that gave up their lives
to be here today
grew up on the island of Shodoshima?
And let me tell you,
those cows had it good.
Frolicking over sun-dappled hillsides,
dining on olive peels
from Japan's oldest plantation.
I'm told one cow can sell
for $40,000, $50,000 wholesale.
Rounding down, I'm probably
looking at 30 quarters.
Given the average rate
of cooling, once I kill the AC,
you've probably got, what, 45 minutes
before your half a million dollars
of umami-flavored goodness
will be worth less than a shinbone.
I don't know what they had
in those shipment containers.
I don't.
But you know where they went.
Yes. Yes, I do.
I didn't know the FBI
investigated car accidents.
We're not here about your
husband's death, Mrs. McClaire.
We'd like to talk about his
relationship with Mara James.
What did she tell you?
She signed a nondisclosure agreement.
Mara James is dead.
She was murdered.
Oh, my God.
That's awful.
You said she signed a contract.
[SIGHS]
My husband had an affair
that resulted in a child.
Ms. James approached our attorneys.
Jonathan had only recently
passed, and so I settled.
We didn't find a record
of any settlement.
It was sealed.
My husband's career was based on...
[INHALES SHAKILY]
...the appearance of a happy marriage.
Even now, I live off the book sales.
And sales would dry up if anyone
knew he'd been unfaithful.
So you agreed to a secret settlement.
Well, there was a DNA test, so I
know it was his child, but...
we were so happy.
I still can't believe he stepped
outside of our marriage.
♪♪
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
What am I looking at?
The victims we found eight years ago.
Their bodies were so decomposed
they didn't have C-section scars
like Mara's,
but take a look at this.
Pockmarks along the pelvic bone
caused by ligaments tearing
during childbirth.
Our victims were all mothers.
If they all had babies, did they
all have secret settlements?
The point of secret settlements
is that they're secret.
It could take months to track
down the right courthouses
- and secure warrants.
- That's what I thought,
but it's a good thing we know a criminal
who can cut through the red tape.
- [SNORING]
- [DOOR OPENS]
♪♪
[CHUCKLES]
[DRAWER OPENS]
I'll be obliged to take a sniff
in your company.
Yes, I understand your feeling
of obligation.
Ahh!
♪♪
Mickey, how long have you been
the file clerk for the courthouse?
Must be going on 25 years.
Shepherding a national database
of pleadings and motions,
suits and countersuits.
Everyone's dirty little secrets.
- [PENCIL SCRAPING]
- Pearl's angina has been acting up.
Set us back a little more than usual.
Huh.
You're worth it at twice the price.
And Pearl is priceless.
[LAUGHS]
Brother, you sure know
how to wet my whistle.
Yes, sir, you most certainly do.
Mmm!
Ahh!
So, what can I do you for?
Mr. Reddington pays for
his wife's angina medication?
Medication, hospital visits.
I get the impression he pays for
whatever the file clerk needs.
What have you found in the settlements?
I'm hoping it's enough
to justify the, shall we say,
unorthodox way in which we obtained them.
The victims we're aware of
all had children out of wedlock
with very wealthy men,
and they all made paternity
claims against the fathers,
which were all settled.
And within weeks of the agreements,
each of the women were murdered.
And the children?
We haven't found a single one.
- So, what have we found?
- Death certificates.
Turns out Jonathan McClaire
wasn't the only father who died
before the mother of his child.
They all did.
So five mothers who died
soon after giving birth,
and five fathers who died
soon after conception.
The men died in at least four states,
all in crazy accidents...
helicopter crash, a pileup on I-80.
Each event was investigated, but cleared.
No foul play. Nothing to connect them.
Nothing except for a name. Nyle Hatcher.
He signed one of their death
certificates in Pennsylvania,
which I thought was pretty odd,
considering he's a mortician in Bethesda.
So I kept digging.
Turns out he ID'd another victim
in Delaware
and notified next of kin
in West Virginia.
COOPER: Doesn't make any sense.
A mortician from Bethesda
dealing with bodies from places
like Delaware and West Virginia.
According to his employment
records, he used to operate
a funeral home outside Rehoboth Beach.
Makes sense.
He had access to the cemetery.
And no one would question why
a mortician was hanging around.
- Did you get an address?
- 452 Elm,
the same as the mortuary
he currently operates...
Sweet Rest Funeral Home.
Keen, Ressler, get going.
Aram, pull a warrant.
When you got the settlements
from Reddington,
did he say anything about Dembe's imam?
He got a lead on the smugglers,
[SIGHING] and I think he's going
to pay them a visit.
I don't suppose it would do
any good to remind him
that's our job.
He knows.
He just doesn't care.
DONNA: Mr. Hatcher's out today.
- [CELLPHONE RINGING]
- Said he won't be in until Monday.
Said it's a family matter.
- Did he say where he was going?
- No.
- [RINGING CONTINUES]
- He's not answering.
Do you have any other way
of reaching him?
Not anymore.
He used to keep an apartment upstairs.
Now he only has his office.
We're gonna need
his current home address.
And access to that office.
Um, okay, but it's private.
I'm not allowed in there.
Well, that's okay. I am.
This is a warrant.
[DOOR OPENS]
♪♪
What the hell?
This woman, he's following her.
He's got all kinds of data.
♪♪
Keen, what is it?
I'm not sure I want to know.
♪♪
Kendra. Hi.
- I'm, um, Agent Mojtabai.
- [DOOR CLOSES]
You're, uh... You're not under arrest.
- Could've fooled me.
- Yeah. About that...
Let me... Let me get that for you.
[KEYS JINGLING]
If I'm not under arrest, why am I here?
To talk about a man named Nyle Hatcher.
In my line of work, I meet lots of men.
Right, um...
This one runs a funeral home.
And...
he murders women.
Yeah, I know the guy.
Hatcher was in Baltimore yesterday.
The ferry-boat accident.
Sixteen people drowned.
DMORT was deployed
to identify the victims.
The Disaster Mortuary
Operational Response Teams.
When there's a mass-casualty event,
morticians are brought in
to help identify the bodies,
assess cause of death.
The country is divided by region,
and based on where the victims
were found,
Hatcher operates with
Region III, which includes
D.C., Virginia, Delaware,
Pennsylvania, and Maryland.
Which is why a Bethesda
mortician gets access
to rich men at crime scenes
up and down the East Coast.
Well, we know how Hatcher
interacted with the dead men.
But we still have no idea
what part he played... if any...
in the paternity cases
or the deaths of the mothers.
Actually, we do.
KENDRA: He didn't want to hook up.
I thought he did, but when I got there,
he knew everything about me...
family, money problems.
He said he could fix all that.
By getting you pregnant and
suing the father for paternity.
He said no one would get hurt,
that a rich dude
would be a little less rich.
And the baby?
He told me about these safe-haven laws
where you leave babies at fire stations
and they get adopted.
Adopted.
Because the father would already be dead.
Run that by me again.
We found sperm in his office.
There was a thermos, and in it,
uh, there was a sample.
- Sperm from a dead man?
- The rich dead man.
The one Hatcher s-selected
from his DMORT assignment.
Did the men use a-a donor bank?
Is that where he got the samples?
We don't think so.
Then what exactly do you think?
Hatcher inseminated the women
using semen he extracted
from the corpses.
Apparently, sperm is viable
up to 36 hours postmortem.
He extracts the sperm,
impregnates the mother,
who then makes an embarrassing
paternity claim
that's backed up by DNA.
Now, rather than risk a scandal,
the widow hushes it up
with a secret settlement
and no one's the wiser
because dead men tell no tales.
Even about their seed.
What about Kendra Taylor?
Is she pregnant?
You never met Roger Ashby?
No, the hookup was
supposed to be tomorrow.
Is that what Hatcher told you,
it was gonna be a hookup?
He didn't exactly say. Why?
Because Roger Ashby died yesterday
in a ferry-boat accident.
Like I said, all I know
is the hookup was gonna be
tomorrow, and after that,
I was supposed to make a claim
for child support.
Once the settlement was finalized,
Hatcher would take the money,
and you'd end up dead.
That's the last of it.
The money for you and your meal ticket
will be wired to the account
by end of business today.
[BABY COOING]
Her name is Lily.
We're done here.
Hey, um, guys, so, uh...
Kendra says that
she and the target never met.
But that Hatcher told her
she'd be impregnated tomorrow.
By a man who died yesterday.
So what am I missing?
The birds and the bees? [CHUCKLES]
Lemme tell you,
there's a whole new wrinkle.
PARK: I accessed Hatcher's hard drive.
He had a list of the fathers
and how much the widows agreed to pay.
We know all that
from the secret settlements.
You know almost all of it.
There was another name. Abraham Geller.
Wealthy hedge-fund guy.
Died in a plane crash 10 months ago.
Which might mean someone just
gave birth to his child...
and may have signed a settlement offer.
Or her death warrant.
You two, find the lawyer
who handles the Geller estate.
See what he knows.
Um, the birds and the bees?
What's the new wrinkle?
[SIGHS]
Did the transfer go through?
Just. You did well.
The hard part's over.
Your cut's over a hundred
thousand dollars, Angela.
So drop off the child
and meet me at Cedar Wind.
I promise you, when you get
what's coming to you,
your life will change forever.
[CELLPHONE BEEPS]
♪♪
Agents Ressler and Park, FBI.
Uh, what can I do for you?
Was a paternity claim made
against Abraham Geller?
I don't discuss my clients' cases.
This isn't about your client.
It's about a woman's life.
I'm sure you can appreciate
this is privileged information.
Yes, but it's
a life-threatening situation.
What you know could save
Angela Hendrickson's life.
- Has she been here?
- Yeah.
To chisel a decent family
out of a small fortune.
So she signed a settlement
agreement. You wired the money?
I did. Less than an hour ago.
♪♪
[BABY CRYING]
Mm.
I thought you'd be alone.
I... couldn't leave her.
I know it wasn't what we agreed to.
Oh, no, don't give it another thought.
[SIGHS HAPPILY] I'm glad she's here.
I think every child should have
a loving home.
Just not yours.
[CRYING INTENSIFIES]
♪♪
I found her. Angela Hendrickson.
Now, she's not answering our
calls, but she received a call
outside a Rockville Fire station
30 minutes ago,
and her cell just pinged
a tower off county road 75.
What's the green area?
That is Cedar Wind Cemetery
in Livingston.
[RINGING]
Oh, cemetery. That's bad.
- Ressler.
- That's, uh... That's really bad.
Ressler, we have a location.
Keen will meet you on-site.
♪♪
[BABY COOING]
[BABY CRYING]
♪♪
Aww. Hey, baby.
We're almost finished.
We'll be home soon.
Oh, my.
Angela, I am so sorry.
I never meant for you to see this.
[CRYING CONTINUES]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS]
♪♪
[BANGING ON DOOR]
[BANGING CONTINUES]
- Yeah?
- Jalal?
Who are you?
A friend from the mosque.
Aah! [GRUNTS]
[GUNFIRE]
JALAL: Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Okay, okay! Okay! [BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GRUNTS]
Go ahead.
♪♪
Where is Imam Asmal?
I don't know. I don't.
- I'm sorry.
- DEMBE: You do.
Answer the question.
HATCHER: Hello, little girl.
We'll be home real soon.
[SIRENS WAILING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
- Good heavens.
- [BABY CRYING]
Hands! Put your hands in the air!
Got a baby here.
- Where is she?!
- [CRYING CONTINUES]
Angela Hendrickson ...where?! I don't...
I don't know who that is.
Where is she, Nyle?
[CRYING CONTINUES]
Which grave? I have no...
Answer me!
I have no earthly idea what you mean!
He doesn't want her to suffer,
so she's sedated,
but she may still be alive.
We need to fan out.
We're looking for a fresh grave.
There can't be many.
[MUFFLED COUGHING]
How do we get to the basement?
I don't have a basement.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS]
♪♪
[CREAKING, RATTLING]
Morgan.
♪♪
[CREAKING, SCRAPING]
Hey! I got something!
♪♪
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
I feel something!
♪♪
[PANTING] She's got a pulse.
Get on the radio! Call the paramedics!
[GRUNTS]
♪♪
What the hell?
_
♪♪
Womens were brutalized,
how many were they?
I try not to think about them.
[PAPER RUSTLING]
♪♪
It wasn't personal.
I needed hosts willing to break the law,
and they did that just by
showing up at my hotel room.
Desperate and broke...
And what... dispensable?
It isn't my fault that nobody
cares when a prostitute dies.
No, people care. Families care.
This was never about killing those women.
Agent Keen, I have spent my life
surrounded by death...
surrounded by the pain
that comes with life's end,
the futility of it all.
It's a lonely existence.
One that I thought money could change.
So I came up with a way to steal money
from people that wouldn't care
that it was missing...
the dead.
I like to think of them as "donors."
But the donors required hosts...
women who, sadly, needed to die
to protect the plan...
which is why I chose women
who needed to be freed
from their otherwise insufferable lives.
Finally, the plan requires a child.
What did you do with the children?
Well, I tell all the mothers
that I plan to give the newborns away.
Some mother don't like that,
and some, like Angela,
even try to keep their babies.
That upset me at first, until I realized
that the money those children
provided me wasn't the solution.
The children were the solution.
What does that mean?
It means I couldn't leave them
at the fire station
like I thought.
Means I needed them.
Means I couldn't let them go,
that they needed me.
Needed you?
Forging the adoption paperwork
wasn't cheap,
but money isn't a problem for me.
I just didn't want any of those
kids to grow up alone...
- [LAUGHS]
- [SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
HATCHER: ...like me, without a family.
They needed sisters and brothers.
Where are the kids, Nyle?
They're home.
They have all they need.
A loving father.
Unbelievable financial resources.
What's gonna happen to those kids?
What are they gonna say
when they find out what you did?
Oh, don't tell them what I did.
They don't need to know.
They gave me such a precious gift.
I mean, I was dead.
They brought me back to life.
All that matters are those kids' lives.
And with you in prison, they're
gonna be a whole lot better.
Imam Asmal.
I'm telling you I don't know.
Who are they?
Refugees seeking asylum.
Imam Asmal knows nothing of this.
I thought the FBI took him
because they thought he did.
And you have no ties to Tahrir al-Sham.
Me? I'm trying to save them
from Tahrir al-Sham.
The United States has made it
illegal for them to come here.
- [CELLPHONE RINGING]
- But the Prophet Muhammed teaches us
not to obey the created
if it means disobeying the Creator.
- Harold?
- CTD traced a cellphone
belonging to one of the extremists.
They traced it to a safe house
in West Adams.
Units are en route.
They're not extremists.
They're humanitarians.
Humanitarians took the imam?
How long do we have
before the troops arrive?
You are at the safe house.
[SIGHS] It's feeling less and
less safe with every second.
[MAZZY STAR'S "INTO DUST" PLAYING]
♪♪
PARK: Looks like your cold-case
theory was right, Liz.
I confirmed it.
He set the money aside for the children.
A guy with a conscience
who does what he did,
that's way scarier
than a straight psychopath.
We should tell the widows their
husbands didn't cheat on them.
- ARAM: And the kids?
- ♪ Still ♪
What's being done about the kids?
Child Services is reaching out
to the families of both parents.
- ♪ Falling ♪
- Hopefully someone will step up.
Hi.
I'm Margaret. Mm-hmm.
- ♪ Breathless and on ♪
- I'm your grandma.
[LAUGHS] Aren't you the sweetest?
- ♪ Again ♪
- You have your mother's eyes.
What about Angela?
Will she get to keep her child?
She's under house arrest, awaiting trial.
But mothers can keep their
infants with them in prison
for up to 18 months.
♪ Falling ♪
♪♪
♪ Breathless and on ♪
Ah. Please tell me you're hungry.
- ♪ Again ♪
- Tonight's special is wagyu beef.
So this is what it's all about.
Asylum seekers.
Counterterrorism division is
looking for extremists that don't exist
when they should be looking
for Dembe's imam.
His kidnapping is completely
unrelated and, as yet, unsolved.
I checked with MPD on my way over.
They've got nothing.
No forensics. No witnesses.
- ♪ Beside me ♪
- Sakiya said the same.
I told her to double-check
everything, but...
I'm afraid it's a diminishing return.
How's he holding up?
♪ Around, broken in two ♪
It's hard for him.
Especially since he knows I'm to blame.
You?
People close to me
are often in harm's way.
♪ Till your eyes shed ♪
Dembe's imam is not close to you.
- ♪ Into dust ♪
- No. But Dembe is.
I don't think whoever did this
is interested in extremists
- ♪ Like two strangers ♪
- or clerics and refugees.
♪ Turning into dust ♪
I think they're interested in me.
♪♪
♪ Till my hands shook ♪
- ♪ With the weight ♪
- At first, I thought you screwed up,
that Koslov ran because he knew
you were following him.
But then I realized
Ilya wasn't scared of you.
You're the one who's scared.
Reddington got to you.
Ilya Koslov has information that
could save my mother's life.
And you helped prevent me
from finding it.
The least you can do is tell me why.
You have powerful enemies.
[BREATHES DEEPLY]
I had no idea he was one of them.
- ♪ I could possibly be fading ♪
- The Sikorsky Archive.
What's that?
Before Reddington warned me off,
I had a mic trained on Ilya's apartment.
- ♪ Or have ♪
- That archive, whatever it is,
he's obsessed with it.
If Koslov has information
that could save a woman's life,
my guess it's in that archive.
♪ I could feel myself ♪
- ♪ Growing colder ♪
- [DOOR OPENS]
- ♪ I could feel myself ♪
- [FOOTSTEPS]
- ♪ Under your fate ♪
- We have a lot to talk about.
Who are you?
How about you let me ask the questions?
♪ Under ♪
♪♪
♪ Your fate ♪
What, you change your number?
That's cold.
- I got nothing to say to you.
- Maybe not.
But I got something to say to you,
and, trust me,
you're gonna want to hear it.
- ♪ It was you ♪
- That's Ray Field...
until next week, when they
break ground on the strip mall.
- ♪ Breathless and torn ♪
- Digging up Ray Field?
Yeah, baby brother.
And all the secrets under it.
♪ I could feel my eyes ♪
Yes.
- ♪ Turning into dust ♪
- I'll tell him.
- [BEEP]
- They're at the safe house on Vermont.
- ♪ And two strangers ♪
- Jalal asked me to thank you.
Happy ending for them.
- ♪ Turning into dust ♪
- For you, not so much.
[COUGHS]
- Raymond.
- [COUGHS]
[INHALES DEEPLY]
I'm fine.
- [KNOCK ON DOOR]
- [COUGHING]
- ♪ Turning into dust ♪
- I'm fine.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
♪♪
- I found something.
- [DOOR CLOSES]
A fingerprint on the corner
of the imam's desk.
Could you identify it?
I could. But, uh...
But what?
Belongs to a man who's been
in prison for 15 years.
Arturo Ruel.
How can that be?
I don't know. Perhaps Raymond will.
Raymond.
♪♪
Raymond!
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS]
♪♪