.
♪♪♪
[ Door bangs ]
Unit 5‐7, requesting
additional units
to Brewster housing complex.
Looking for one suspect,
white male, possibly armed.
Have units roll Code 2 ‐‐
no lights or sirens.
[ Static ]
We lucky today, partner?
One way to find out.
♪ What you got goin' on? ♪
♪♪♪
♪ Behind those eyes closed ♪
♪ Holdin' on ♪
♪♪♪
♪ I don't want another ♪
♪ Day to break ♪
[ Gunshot ]
I got him, I got him!
♪ Take our, steal our ♪
♪ Night away ♪
Central! Shots fired!
Shots fired!
Ressler's been hit!
My partner is down!
[ Gunshots ]
Roll ambulance to
my location, immediately!
Dispatcher:
Central, copy.
EMT to Brewster
housing complex.
Officer down, officer down.
[ Sighs ]
I told you to take
the money, Bob.
♪ Warm shadow ♪
The rest of us did.
♪♪♪
I'll look after Lisa
and the boys.
[ Sighs ]
♪♪♪
[ Sighs deeply ]
You ever think about Dad?
What about him?
Just...
You wake up one day,
kiss the wife and kids,
you go on the job ‐‐
you don't know it's gonna be the
last five minutes of your life.
What was he thinking
right before that?
What he wanted to have
for dinner, or the gas bill?
We don't need to talk
about it.
♪♪♪
You've seen a lot of people
get killed, right?
Is it always that...
meaningless?
Yeah.
♪♪♪
Mm. Almost home.
Been a while since
you've been back, huh?
A few years at least?
What do you think this is?
A vacation for me?
Do you think I ‐‐
I want to be here?
I know you don't want
to be here.
Mom knows, though. I told her
you were coming to town.
You told Mom?
Mm.
You do realize that if something
goes wrong tonight,
we both end up going
straight to jail?
You get that, right?
Relax.
[ Sighs ] It's just Mom.
Who's she gonna tell?
[ Indistinct conversations ]
So, you got anybody
special
back in D. C., Donnie?
[ Chuckles ]
When am I gonna start seeing
some nieces and nephews?
Uh, no one special right now,
Aunt Cindy.
But I'm looking.
I got my eyes open.
Ben: Is it cool being
an FBI agent, Uncle Don?
You got a gun?
‐I do carry a weapon, Ben, yeah.
Man:
How long you around?
What's this big case
we heard about?
‐Big case?
‐The one you're in town for.
Robby said
it was something big?
‐Ma, I told you it was top, uh‐‐
‐Confidential.
...is the word we use
at the Bureau ‐‐ confidential.
Lisa: Look at this.
Both my boys
under the same roof.
Don, did Robby tell you
about his company expanding?
He got himself that collector's
car you rode here in.
And he bought me
a fancy new watch.
It's nothing, Ma.
Just got a new garage,
and we can do twice
as many cars now, so...
I'm just happy
you're home, Don.
I wish your father
could be here
to see how great both
his children turned out.
He'd be so proud.
♪♪♪
Donnie, what am I gonna tell
your father when he gets home?
Principle Neill's a liar.
[ Sighs ]
I thought we were past all this.
You can't keep
skipping class.
What am I gonna learn
in a classroom
that I can't learn
out in the real world, anyway?
By "real world," you mean
getting baked with
your wastoid friends out behind
the Farmer Jack's every day?
Stay out of this,
Officer Asshat.
We all know you're only joining
the academy
for the cavity searches.
‐Loitering's a crime, you know.
One of these days, it'll be me
slapping the cuffs on you.
Mm, maybe I'll learn
something useful in prison.
Like dice.
[ Doorbell rings ]
♪♪♪
[ Door opens ]
Lisa: Tom?
What is it?
Markin: Lisa...
It's Bob.
Something's happened.
Can I come in?
Wait, wait...
[ Sobbing ]
Please, Tom. No.
It can't be.
Not my husband.
Please, no.
[ Sobbing ]
♪♪♪
Lisa: Everything
alright, Don?
Yeah.
J‐Just a little tired.
We drove all night, so, uh,
I'm gonna have to get
a little shut eye.
I'm sorry.
‐Oh, of course.
I put fresh sheets
on your old bed.
You remember the way,
don't you?
Of course.
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪♪
[ Footsteps approaching ]
[ Clears throat ]
There we are.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I ‐‐ I didn't know ‐‐
What, Mom was gonna host
a family reunion?
Good call on that one.
[ Chuckles ]
You know how she is.
She gets excited.
What can I say?
Again, I'm sorry, alright?
What you should be sorry for
is lying to her.
Don't think for a second
I'm fooled
by this whole vintage car
and Rolex routine.
What are you up to,
Robby?
You know what?
This may come as a shock
to you, Don ‐‐
Agent Ressler,
world policeman ‐‐
I am not a screw‐up
anymore.
Well, if you're such a success,
what are you doing
living at home,
sleeping in our old room?
I'm just between apartments.
[ Exhales sharply ]
Go to hell.
♪♪♪
You know, somebody had to
look out for Mom.
You won't do it.
Let's just get this
over with.
[ Clears throat ]
Okay.
You remember
the old dirt field?
They're gonna turn this
into an outdoor mall.
They break ground tomorrow.
If they find
what's under that dirt...
So it's now or never.
I watched the site overnight
last week.
They have
one night watchman.
Guy makes his rounds
every hour or two.
Half the time,
he's asleep in his car.
Now, see this?
There's a gap in that gate
big enough
for both of us to fit through
without making a sound.
How's that for recon?
Alright.
We're gonna need shovels,
nothing too heavy...
flashlights,
low‐wattage ‐‐
can't be too bright,
nothing with halogen bulbs.
Bleach ‐‐ we're gonna need at
least three quarts, maybe more.
Wow.
Big project, huh?
Yeah.
Septic tank.
♪♪♪
♪ In my eyes ♪
♪ Indisposed ♪
♪ In disguises no one knows ♪
♪ Hides the face,
lies the snake ♪
♪ The sun in my disgrace ♪
♪ Boiling heat ♪
The hell are you doing?
Grieving.
What's it to you?
♪ 'Neath the black
the sky looks dead ♪
♪ Call my name
through the cream ♪
Who are these people?
Cool it.
They're here for Mom.
Yeah?
Who's here for Dad?
♪♪♪
Markin:
How you boys holding up?
You need anything?
Yep.
Refill.
♪♪♪
He's drunk?
You're surprised?
[ Door closes ]
♪♪♪
This was Dad's.
That's St. Michael,
patron saint of police officers.
Found it in his
personal effects.
[ Sighs ]
He would've wanted it to go
to the next cop in the family.
[ Cellphone rings ]
♪♪♪
♪ Black hole sun ♪
♪ Won't you come ♪
♪ And wash away the rain ♪
[ Sighs ]
[ Door closes ]
♪ Black hole sun ♪
Markin: Hang on.
♪ Won't you come ♪
Alright, I'm outside. Go ahead.
Don't feed me that.
♪ Black hole sun ♪
We gave the guy a chance.
♪ Won't you come ♪
Nobody wanted this.
It's cleaned up.
♪ And wash away the rain ♪
Just heard from forensics ‐‐
no further investigation.
♪ Black hole sun ♪
It's a good shooting.
We're safe.
♪ Won't you come ♪
‐♪ Black hole sun,
black hole sun ♪
[ Tapping on glass ]
Pop the trunk.
♪ Won't you come ♪
‐♪ Black hole ♪
♪♪♪
[ Car doors close,
engine starts ]
[ Cellphone dialing ]
[ Ringing tone ]
We've got eyes on them.
I'll keep you posted.
[ Tires squealing ]
♪♪♪
.
[ Chains rattling ]
♪♪♪
‐Tommy Markin did it.
‐Shut up, Donnie.
You don't know
what you're saying.
I heard the call!
I was right there!
Tommy was talking
about Dad.
Maybe he didn't
pull the trigger,
but he had something
to do with it, I'm sure.
You're drunk.
I know what I heard.
Maybe it was another case.
He was Dad's best friend.
He's practically our uncle ‐‐
Maybe we can prove it?
Maybe we can prove it.
Like ‐‐ Like on TV
or something.
We ‐‐ We could get him
to confess to us.
That's not how it works.
You need evidence ‐‐
documents, a recording ‐‐
I'll get them.
I trust Tommy Markin,
okay?
Dad trusted him,
I trust him.
Why?
'Cause you both wear
the same stupid badge?
Look, I know you need someone
to blame for this ‐‐
I have someone to blame!
We just need to prove it!
Jesus, Don!
How bad do you need to be
the center of attention
every single time?!
Don't mention it again!
Don't bring it up to Mom.
She feels bad enough.
Let it go.
♪♪♪
61, 62, 63, 64, 65, 66...
Can't believe
it's actually working.
[ Man coughing ]
I thought you said
that he ‐‐
Shh!
I guess he's off
his schedule.
♪♪♪
Get down, get down!
Aah!
♪♪♪
Alright, looks like I'm gonna be
doing all the digging.
[ Sighs ]
♪♪♪
Sure this is it?
I'd know it
like it was yesterday.
This is it. Dig fast.
I'll keep an eye out
for the turnkey.
[ Glass shatters ]
♪♪♪
[ Glass crunching ]
I heard you before
you even put your pants on
this morning, Donnie.
The hell are you
doing here?
What did you do
to my dad?
Wrong place,
wrong time, kid.
Let me show you the door.
I know you had something to do
with him getting shot.
I heard you.
On the phone.
You're coming with me
to tell the cops everything.
I am the cops.
Donnie, you're young.
You're grieving.
You're not thinking
straight.
We can figure out a way
to pay for the window,
but ‐‐
[ Gun cocks ]
Recognize this?
It was Dad's.
Donnie, it's a tragedy
what happened.
What are you gonna do?
Shoot me?
Shoot a cop?
Do you even have a plan?
Just tell me it's true!
You've already gotten yourself
into enough trouble
to break
your mother's heart.
Don't make it worse.
You don't want this
on your head.
I'm gonna give you
one more chance.
You give me that gun,
or your life is over,
young man.
You think you're tough?
Your dad was tough.
Your brother's tough.
You don't even have
the balls to p‐‐
♪♪♪
[ Shovel scraping ]
[ Coughs ]
It's been a while.
You remember Tommy Markin,
don't you, Don?
♪♪♪
.
Donnie, what did you do?
[ Breathing shakily ]
♪ Pack your things ♪
I didn't know
who else to call.
He killed Dad, Robby.
Did he admit it?
He was going to.
♪ Leave somehow ♪
H‐He would've. I know it.
♪♪♪
♪ Blackbird song ♪
Donnie, I need you
to listen to me carefully
♪ Is over now ♪
and answer my questions.
You got that?
Did anyone see you
come in here?
No.
Did Markin alert anyone
when he saw you?
Did he make any calls?
No.
How long has it been
since the gunshot?
I don't know. Uh...
15, maybe 20 minutes.
Then nobody heard it.
Or at least
no one reported it.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Donnie.
Go home.
Wipe Dad's gun off and put it
back where you found it.
Don't say anything to Mom.
Don't say anything to anyone.
♪ Mouths are dry ♪
Forget this happened.
Understood?
♪ River runs ♪
What are you gonna do?
I'll take care of this.
♪ Hands are tied ♪
Don't say another word.
Just go.
♪ Preacher sighs ♪
♪♪♪
♪ Pack your things ♪
Robby:
You ever lose sleep at night
'cause of what we did back then?
♪ Leave somehow ♪
Some nights.
Not many.
Ever wish you could
take it back?
♪ Blackbird song ♪
This man killed our father.
Then stood at his wake
and lied to our faces.
He was a disgrace
to the badge he wore.
♪ Is over now ♪
The one you were going to wear.
The one I wear every day.
No, this scumbag got everything
that was coming to him.
So, no.
I wouldn't take it back.
You?
♪ Ohhhh ♪
Ah, we better get going.
Night watchman will be
coming soon.
♪ Don't be scared ♪
♪ I'm still here ♪
♪♪♪
♪ No more time ♪
♪ For crying, dear ♪
♪♪♪
[ Tires screech, engine revs ]
Listen, Robby, look, I ‐‐
I should say, uh...
should say that I'm sorry.
About what?
What I said earlier,
back at the house.
Look, I‐I've been
hard on you.
I left this place behind,
and you stayed,
and that was ‐‐
that was the harder choice,
and I should give you
credit for it.
For everything.
All your success.
Work, everything.
[ Lid rattles, closes ]
Thank you, Don.
Look, I was a prick
when we were younger,
and I'm the reason why we're
taking care of this now, but...
you had my back
that night.
Of course I did.
You're my brother.
I never thanked you.
♪♪♪
Look, you saved me.
That night, everything
in my life changed.
Well, you might've noticed,
it wasn't exactly
the same for me, either.
Looks like you're doing
pretty good now.
Hey, maybe you could take me
by this garage
while I'm still in town?
Yeah, cool.
[ Engine revving ]
I'd like that.
[ Tires screeching ]
♪♪♪
Robby, tell me
that was random.
Okay, I can explain.
♪♪♪
.
Oh, you don't say?
I was losing money,
so I hired a bunch of guys.
I thought they were
stand‐up guys.
And, uh...anyway,
I needed some fast cash.
Couldn't stand for
another failure, Donnie.
Who'd you borrow money from?
Definitely not the banks.
Those places, you walk in,
they don't even look at you ‐‐
Robby.
I borrowed it
from a local guy.
What do you mean,
a connected kind of local guy?
Yeah, the Albanian type.
The mob?
The Albanian mob?
How much money
did you borrow?
50K.
It was 30% vig on it.
And that was
like six months ago.
[ Laughs ]
So it's closer
to 150K now, so...
That's why they took the car,
you know, as collateral.
♪♪♪
I had to try something.
[ Telephone rings ]
Is there anything else
you're not telling me?
No, I swear.
That's it.
Hey, man.
It's for you.
♪♪♪
‐Who is this?
‐We have your car.
And the cargo in the trunk.
Jakov Mitko wants
to see you both.
Who's Jakov Mitko?
Your brother knows.
He knows where, too.
Don't be late.
[ Click ]
♪♪♪
You know the thing
about plants?
They are obedient.
A little love,
a little care ‐‐
they do exactly
what they are supposed to.
They grow.
They give back.
Oxygen, flowers.
They are uncomplicated.
Anyone can respect that,
yes?
You must be the brother
from D. C.
Everyone thought I was crazy
to loan money
to a guy
whose brother was FBI.
I said, "Wait and see."
I don't think in a million years
I could've seen this.
Listen, Jakov,
I'm gonna get your money.
Every last penny of it.
This isn't about money
anymore.
I don't understand this.
He has the car.
That's what this is about.
Ah.
Voilà.
I don't know
who Detective 4818
of the Detroit Police Department
was ‐‐
but he's seen better days.
Just tell us what you want.
I was going to burn down your
garage, just to prove I could.
I thought that was
your only asset.
But now that your brother
is here,
I know I was wrong.
An FBI agent?
Now that's
a whole other thing.
At the field office of the FBI
here in Detroit,
there is a room called
Department 12.
I have never seen it.
I am told it is mostly
computers.
Computers that an agent
like yourself can access.
Go to that room, and bring me
back a file labeled "432."
What is it?
Have that file back here
by 5:00 p. m. today.
If you do that,
I will give you back the car
and everything that's in it.
And as an added incentive,
I will wipe your
brother's debt clean.
Hey.
I know
what you're gonna say.
♪♪♪
Okay, fine,
I deserved that.
You know what Department 12 is,
Robby?
It's the office UCs file
their sealed reports to.
Now, in case you forgot watching
"Miami Vice" as kids,
UC stands for "undercover."
So, whoever's name's in there
is gonna get killed
'cause I gotta run
that psycho's little errand.
I'm not an idiot.
I'm not an idiot!
Don't treat me like one!
♪♪♪
And you're not gonna do
what he's asking you to do!
It'll destroy you.
Yeah, and if I don't,
he's gonna take those remains
and he's gonna turn them in,
and it's gonna destroy
both of us.
I'll take
full responsibility.
We both know I can't
let you do that, okay?
I killed that guy.
Donnie, Donnie ‐‐
No, this is my mess.
You still don't get it.
It isn't only your mess.
♪♪♪
Robby: It was just me
and the body.
You're shocked what your brain
can come up with
when you're on
autopilot like that.
♪♪♪
[ Shovel scraping ]
I thought a lot about
how most people's lives hinge
on a few key moments.
[ Markin moans ]
[ Markin coughs ]
♪♪♪
I think mine only had
one moment,
and then it was over.
♪♪♪
[ Rasping ] Robby...
Please...
I know you had Dad killed,
Tommy.
Donnie told me the truth.
Letting me die...
won't make us even...
♪♪♪
[ Crying ]
You took my father from me.
How could you?
It ‐‐ It was...
business...
In that moment, I suddenly
had this clear thought.
And I knew I was the only person
that could protect you, Don.
From Tommy Markin,
and anyone else like him
who might come along.
I had no choice...
[ Shovel thuds ]
I finished what you started.
[ Breathing heavily ]
I did it for you.
For me.
And for Daddy.
In the end, all I was
thinking about was you.
I was protecting
your future.
Yeah, but why?
Why didn't you tell me?
What ‐‐ W‐Why keep this
a secret all these years?
I did that
to protect you, too.
Whatever that night had done
to you, it was driving you.
I carried the weight.
I never regretted it.
Because it did exactly
what I thought it would do.
And what's that?
It made you the person
that you are today.
So it's not your mess.
It's my mess, brother.
I'll turn myself in.
No.
We turn ourselves in.
I left you alone once
to clean up a mess.
I'm not gonna leave you
alone again.
♪♪♪
I killed the man
who killed our father.
I pulled the trigger,
yeah ‐‐
and to protect me,
my brother did the rest.
But we each had
a hand in it.
Look, we know where the body is.
We can take you to it.
But because of
my involvement,
I have to recuse myself from any
part of the rest of this case.
That's why I called you.
I knew you would help.
I ‐‐ I knew you would do
the right thing.
Ressler, I...
I'm not sure what
I'm supposed to say.
Well, say you agree with me
about how we should handle this.
I mean, we arrest those bastards
who took the car ‐‐
for theft, for extortion,
for all the other poison
they pump into the city.
♪♪♪
And then after that...
my brother and I come clean
about what we've done.
I don't know
that I do agree.
After the story
you told me,
after what you've been through
‐‐ both of you ‐‐
No, we have to do
the right thing.
It's important.
Of course, yes,
I will help you.
I just want to make sure
you're prepared
to face the consequences
when the FBI gets their hands
on that vehicle and that body.
Because if we go in and arrest
those people, eventually,
the FBI's gonna
open up that trunk.
And find Tommy Markin.
I know.
Are you really okay with dealing
with the consequences of that?
I've been running from this
my whole life.
I need it to be done.
We both need it to be done.
♪♪♪
[ Button clicks ]
Yeah, this is Agent Keen.
Can I get SAC Patel
in here, please?
Thank you.
[ Receiver clatters ]
I need someone local
to run point with me on this.
We should go over
what the plan is.
[ Sighs ]
[ Train whistle blares ]
♪♪♪
We'll be around the corner,
two blocks away.
12‐second response time,
I'd guess.
Wanna go over/under
on that?
It's gonna be dangerous.
When is it not?
You know, I can still talk
to Patel, call it off.
I have the authority ‐‐
You know, Keen...
I didn't like you
when we first met.
I was wrong.
You're a good agent.
You're the kind of agent
that...
people join the FBI
to try to become.
But you're also
a good person.
Much better person
than I am.
So, whatever happens
out there today,
the Task Force is gonna be
in good hands with you.
♪♪♪
You alright?
This is gonna kill Mom.
Tell me again.
We're doing the right thing?
Yeah, Robby. We are.
We're doing the right thing.
♪♪♪
[ Engine shuts off ]
I would be lying if I said
I wasn't surprised
that you went through
with it.
File 432.
You don't care
who's on it?
That's not my business.
Your brother
is sweating.
And he looks nervous.
It's because it's humid in here
and he loves his car.
How about we see it?
Okay.
Let us go and see it.
♪♪♪
One more thing
before we trade.
What do you want?
A plant?
A nice orchid to go?
[ Chuckles ]
My brother checks out the car
for confirmation.
Come on, Robby, do it.
♪♪♪
[ Coughs ]
My file.
♪♪♪
Looks like we're finished.
Ressler, you're sure
this is what you want?
Actually, I think I might
have a few more projects
I need your help with.
No, this was
a one‐time deal.
Or it wasn't.
I still have the car
and my file.
You sure about that?
The drive is blank.
It's a fake!
We're a go!
Go, go, go, go!
[ Grunts ]
‐FBI! Hands!
‐On the ground!
♪♪♪
East entrance to the greenhouse!
Let's move!
Tradhtar!
I'll grind your guts
to fertilizer!
Hey, you!
♪♪♪
Everyone okay back here?
Yeah.
Your friend just saved my life.
I wouldn't say that.
I don't think
I saved anyone.
♪♪♪
.
Priest: Wait for the Lord
with courage.
Be stouthearted
and wait for the Lord.
And now, I've been told
Detective Ressler's eldest son,
Robert,
would like to say a few words.
♪ I see problems down the line ♪
♪ I know they're not mine ♪
♪♪♪
♪ Don't wash the dirt
off of your hands ♪
♪ Doing the same mistake twice ♪
♪ Making the same mistake
twice ♪
♪♪♪
♪ Come on over ♪
♪ Don't be so caught up ♪
♪ It's not about compromising ♪
I know everyone here
knew my dad.
Had some special version of him
to hold on to.
♪ I know they're not mine ♪
What a good guy he was.
What a good cop.
I kinda wish I had that.
Truth is,
I didn't really know him.
♪ I see darkness
down the line ♪
My version of Dad
is him stomping
into my school...
♪ I know it's not fine ♪
[ Chuckles ]
...fresh from patrol,
furious after I got caught
putting cigarette butts
in the faculty's coffee machine.
♪ Don't wash the dirt
off of your hands ♪
Then he left too soon.
♪ Doing the same mistake twice ♪
And what I have now,
i‐instead of a version of him
to hold onto...
♪ Come over ♪
...is a path to follow.
A path that shows me
how to grow up right...
♪ It's not about compromising ♪
...how to stay out of trouble,
how to be good, like him.
♪ I see problems down the line ♪
Robby:
So, it started with me
only borrowing $50,0000.
♪ I know they're not mine ♪
But with interest,
and the time
that had gone by,
Mitko was demanding
that I pay back $150,000.
That's when he came
after the car...
I don't remember the number
on the badge,
but it was
definitely a cop.
The agent and his brother,
they knew about that.
I would say more, but I want
to make a deal first.
Can you prove any of this?
You go check out the trunk
of that car yourself.
Agent Ressler...
There has been an allegation
made against you
and your brother by the man
we have in the other room.
Yeah, we were
expecting that.
It's a very serious allegation.
♪ Don't let the darkness
eat you up ♪
The thing about
this case is ‐‐
♪♪♪
♪ Don't let the darkness
eat you up ♪
Well, this is
interesting...
♪♪♪
Robby: How is the body
just gone?
I mean, Markin didn't just
get up and walk away.
I think we're good.
I mean, I don't know
exactly what happened,
but I do have
some theories.
I think someone was watching
over us, Robby.
[ Sighs ]
Now what do we do?
Well, I think we can finally
put this behind us and move on.
[ Sighs ]
I need a drink.
[ Door opens ]
♪♪♪
[ Door closes ]
Oh, hi, sweetie.
Were you boys out
all night?
Yeah, it was a...
It was a long one.
Well, did everything
work out okay?
What do you mean?
Did you get Robby
out of the trouble he was in?
I knew something was up.
A mother knows.
You here all of a sudden
on a "case."
The case turned out
as well as possible.
I'm pretty sure
Robby's gonna be okay.
Thank you, Donnie.
Trouble or not,
your brother means well.
He just gets himself
a bit lost sometimes.
[ Scoffs ]
I meant what I said
about your father
being proud
of the both of you.
You know why?
Because you stick together.
♪♪♪
[ Indistinct conversation ]
Robby:
I couldn't do that.
I couldn't just stand in front
of those people and say...
♪♪♪
What could I say?
It's okay.
We got through it.
[ Sniffs ]
Tomorrow will be easier,
and the day after that ‐‐
Maybe you can do better
with this than I did.
♪♪♪
[ Sniffles ]
This is Dad's?
I can't be a cop.
I'm nothing like him.
I don't know
what I am anymore.
♪♪♪
You heading back
to D. C., bud?
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm sure the office
has missed me by now.
[ Chuckles ]
Mom's sure gonna miss you.
Yeah.
I'll call.
As often as I can.
I have something for you.
♪♪♪
Never thought
I'd see that again.
I think it's your turn
to hang onto it a while.
♪♪♪
You don't think
Dad would've wanted the cop
in the family to have it?
No, no.
I think he'd want you
to have it.
♪♪♪
[ Knocking on door ]
Bad time?
No.
No, come in.
Did you do it
to protect me?
You say that
like it's a bad thing.
I'm not gonna ask you
how you did it.
I won't ask what you did
with Markin's body or ‐‐ or ‐‐
or how you even
scrubbed that car clean, but ‐‐
I learned from the best.
Look, I want to know ‐‐
I mean...
Liz, I need to know...
Why?
♪♪♪
You were in trouble.
You needed help.
No, y‐y‐you...
you risked everything.
I mean, if you ‐‐
you'd have been caught ‐‐
Yeah, but I wasn't.
Yeah, but you could've been.
Are you trying to say
thank you?
'Cause if that's
what you're doing,
you're doing
a terrible job of it.
I ‐‐ I ‐‐
I never would've asked you
to take such a huge risk for me.
You didn't ask.
Yeah, but you did it anyway.
It wasn't for you,
knucklehead.
It was for me.
For you?
Look, if you wanna ruin
your life
over something you did
a lifetime ago ‐‐
when you were a teenager,
for God's sake ‐‐
then someday, sure,
I'll let you.
You'll let me.
Yeah, you have my permission
to be a total dipstick.
[ Chuckles ]
So, what am I?
A dipstick
or a knucklehead?
You're a knucklehead
and a dipstick,
and you're someone
that I rely on,
for, like...
everything.
We both know
that's not true.
♪♪♪
Have you looked at my life?
I'm a widow
and a single mom.
A marionette
with a high‐functioning
sociopath pulling my strings.
My grandfather tried
to murder my mother,
and my mother is a legendarily
lethal Russian spy
who moved in next door
without even telling me
who she was.
[ Sighs ]
I mean it.
Have you looked at my life?
I mean, really taken
a close look.
Because it's like
I'm in the middle of a monsoon
that's constantly threatening
to drown me in bad news.
And somewhere in the middle
of that FEMA disaster
of a life...
[Voice breaking] Somewhere
is just a tiny island of calm.
♪♪♪
And if that weren't there,
I would be
swept out to sea.
No, that's never
gonna happen ‐‐
It would
if you weren't here.
But I am.
And it won't.
Come here.
It's never gonna happen.
Not on my watch.
♪♪♪